joomlashine.com 2019-12-28

# Privacy policy | JoomlaShine

This Privacy Policy will comes to effect from 25 May, 2018.

We at JoomlaShine (referred to as "JoomlaShine", "we", "us") respect your privacy and want you to understand how we collect, use, and share data about you. This Privacy Policy covers our data collection practices and describes your rights to access, correct, or restrict our use of your personal data.

This Privacy Policy applies when you visit the JoomlaShine website and use JoomlaShine products (referred to as "Services"). By using the Services, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy.

## What information, how and when do we collect

### Summary

We collect information about you when you:

  * Create an account on our website
  * Communicate with us via contact form
  * Register your copy of the product from the website it's being used

We also collect information, such as usage statistics, by using cookies, server logs, and similar technologies.

### Information You Provide to Us

We collect information that you provide directly to us. For example, we collect information that you provide when you create an account, communicate with us via contact form or interacting in support forum.

The types of information that we may collect include your name, username, password, email address, postal address, phone number, photos, survey responses, payment information such as payment agent details, transactional details, tax information, support queries, forum comments and any other information that you choose to provide.

### Information We Collect Automatically When You Use the Services

When you use our Services, we automatically collect information about you, including:

  * Log Information: We collect log information about your use of the Service, including the type of browser that you use; the time, duration and frequency of your access; pages viewed; your IP address; and the page you visited before visiting our Services.
  * Device Information: We collect information about the computer or mobile device that you use to access our Services, including the hardware model, operating system and version, unique device identifiers, and mobile network information.
  * Location Information: We may collect information about the location of your device each time you use our Services based on your consent to the collection of this information.
  * Information Collected by Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies: We and our service providers collect information using various technologies, including cookies and pixel tags (which are also called clear GIFs, web beacons, or pixels). Cookies are small data files stored on your hard drive or in device memory that help us improve our Services and your experience, and track usage of our Services. Pixel tags are electronic images that may be used in our Services or emails, and track usage of our Services and effectiveness of communications. You can learn more about the types of cookies we and our service providers use by reading our Cookie Policy.

## Why do we need and how do we use your information

### Summary

We use information about you to:

  * Operate, improve, promote, and protect our Services;
  * Communicate with you; and
  * Personalize content.

### Operating our Services

We may use information about you for various purposes related to operating our Services, including to:

  * Provide, maintain, and improve our Services, including to process transactions, develop new products and services, and manage the performance of our Services;
  * Display information about you, for instance, your list of forum topics, which will be visible on your profile;
  * Personalize the Services, for example, to suggest content in which we think you may be interested;
  * Monitor and analyze trends, usage, and activities in connection with our Services;
  * Perform accounting and administrative tasks, and enforce or manage legal claims.
  * Training JoomlaShine staff about how to best serve our user community;

### Communicating With You

We may use information about you for various purposes related to communicating with you, including to:

  * Respond to your comments, questions, and requests, and provide customer service;
  * Communicate with you, in accordance with your account settings, about products, services, and events offered by us and others, to provide news and information that we think will be of interest to you, to conduct online surveys, etc.
  * Send you technical notices, updates, security alerts and support, and administrative messages.

### Advertising

We may use information about you for various advertising activities that match your profiles or interests;

## Sharing your information

### Summary

We do not share information about you in any way other than as described in this Privacy Policy.

We may disclose information about you:

  * To members or social media services, subject to the choices you may make via the Services;
  * To our third-party service providers who help us to operate or improve our Services;
  * To authorities to comply with legal obligations and to protect and defend our rights and property;

## Keeping your information

### Summary

We store personal information on secure servers that are managed by us and our service providers.

### Technical Security

Personal information that we store or transmit is protected by security and access controls, including username and password authentication, two-factor authentication, and data encryption where appropriate.

### Organizational Security

We have redesigned our organizational structure to minimize amount of personnel who have access to our user’s data.

### Data Retention

We retain your personal information for as long as is necessary to provide the services to you and others, and to comply with our legal obligations. If you no longer want us to use your personal information or to provide you with the Services, you can request that we erase your personal information and close your JoomlaShine account.

Please note that if you request the erasure of your personal information we will retain information from deleted accounts as necessary for our legitimate business interests, to comply with the law, prevent fraud, collect fees, resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, assist with investigations, enforce the terms of service and take other actions permitted by law. The information we retain will be handled in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

## Your Rights

### Summary:

  * You can review and change information about you or deactivate your account in your account settings, but we may retain certain information.
  * You have the right to opt out of receiving JoomlaShine’s promotional messages, but you may still receive other non-promotional communications.
  * You may have the right to exercise your data protection rights, including to request that JoomlaShine deletes, amends, or provides you access to your information.

### Account Information

You may update or correct your account information by editing your account settings or by sending a request to [privacy@joomlashine.com](mailto:privacy@joomlashine.com) as described in Section 6. You may also deactivate your account by editing your account settings or by sending an email to [privacy@joomlashine.com](mailto:privacy@joomlashine.com).

### Cookies

See our Cookie Policy for details about these technologies and the information that they collect, use, or share, including how you may be able to control or disable these services.

When you use the Services, there’s certain information that’s recorded which is generally anonymous information and does not reveal your identity. If you’re logged into your account some of this information could be associated with your account.

Occasionally, we will use third party advertising companies to serve ads based on prior visits to our Services. For example, if you visit our websites, you may later see an add for our products and services when you visit a different website.

### Promotional Communications

You can control messages that you receive from JoomlaShine, other members, and third parties by selecting the unsubscribe link in the message that you receive, or by adjusting the communication preferences in your account settings. If you opt out, we may still send you non-promotional messages, such as those about your account or our ongoing business relations.

### Other Data Rights

Data rights that you may have, depending on the country in which you live, include:

  * Objecting to processing of your information, asking us to restrict processing of your information, or requesting the portability of your information.
  * Withdrawing your consent at any time if we have collected and processed your information with your consent. Withdrawing your consent will not affect the lawfulness of any processing that we conducted prior to your withdrawal, nor will it affect processing of your information conducted in reliance on lawful processing grounds other than consent.
  * Complaining to a data protection authority about our collection and use of your information. For more information, please contact your local data protection authority. Contact details for data protection authorities in the European Union are available here.

## Contact Us

Under European data protection law, the controller of your information is JoomlaShine. We will need to change this policy from time to time in order to make sure it stays up to date with the latest legal requirements and any changes to our privacy management practices.

If you have any questions or complaints about this Privacy Policy or how we use your information, please contact [privacy@joomlashine.com](mailto:privacy@joomlashine.com).
